<problem display_name="Exercise 2" group_access="{&quot;51&quot;: [1, 2]}" markdown="null">
  <text>
    <p>
      <b>ESTIMATED TIME TO COMPLETE: 5 minutes</b>
    </p>
    <p>
Consider the following code specification: </p>
    <pre>
def union(set1, set2):
   """
   set1 and set2 are collections of objects, each of which might be empty.
   Each set has no duplicates within itself, but there may be objects that
   are in both sets. Objects are assumed to be of the same type.

   This function returns one set containing all elements from
   both input sets, but with no duplicates.
   """
</pre>
    <p>
Indicate which of the conditions below would combine to make a good black box test suite for the function <code>union</code> by selecting the appropriate choice(s). </p>
    <p>
      <choiceresponse>
        <checkboxgroup direction="vertical">
          <choice correct="true" name="1">
            <span>
              <text><code>set1</code> is an empty set; <code>set2</code> is an empty set</text>
            </span>
          </choice>
          <choice correct="true" name="2">
            <span>
              <text><code>set1</code> is an empty set; <code>set2</code> is of size greater than or equal to 1</text>
            </span>
          </choice>
          <choice correct="true" name="3">
            <span>
              <text><code>set1</code> is of size greater than or equal to 1; <code>set2</code> is an empty set</text>
            </span>
          </choice>
          <choice correct="true" name="4">
            <span>
              <text><code>set1</code> and <code>set2</code> are both nonempty sets which do not contain any objects in common</text>
            </span>
          </choice>
          <choice correct="true" name="5">
            <span>
              <text><code>set1</code> and <code>set2</code> are both nonempty sets which contain objects in common</text>
            </span>
          </choice>
        </checkboxgroup>
      </choiceresponse>
    </p>
    <p>
      <solution>
        <div class="detailed-solution">
          <p>
            <b>Explanation:</b>
          </p>
          <p>A good black box test suite would contain tests for all of the given 
	    conditions! Black-box testing tests the functionality of an application,
	    by looking at the paths through its specifications.</p>
          <p>According to the specifications, the possibilities for <code>set1</code> and <code>set2</code>
	    are as follows: both sets are empty; one of the sets is empty and one has at least one object;
	    both sets are not empty. The tests list all the combinations of those possibilities for 
	    <code>set1</code> and <code>set2</code>. </p>
        </div>
      </solution>
    </p>
  </text>
</problem>
