<problem display_name="Exercise: hand" group_access="{&quot;51&quot;: [1, 2]}" markdown="null" weight="5.0">
  <text>
    <p>
      <b>ESTIMATED TIME TO COMPLETE: 14 minutes</b>
    </p>
    <p>In this problem, you'll be asked to read through an object-oriented implementation
      of the hand from the word game problem of Problem Set 4. You'll then be asked to implement one of
      its methods. Note that the implementation of the object-oriented version of the hand is a bit
      different than how we did things with the functional implementation; pay close attention to 
      doc strings and read through the implementation carefully.</p>
    <p>To begin: Download <a href="/static/hand.py">hand.py</a> 
      and read through the file. Be sure to understand what's going on in the file. Make a few instances of 
      the <code>Hand</code> class, and play around with the existing methods.</p>
    <p>When you have completed reading through the file, implement the <code>update</code> method.</p>
    <p>Paste the entire <code>Hand</code> class in the box below.</p>
    <p> The <code>__str__</code> method is this:</p>
    <pre>    def __str__(self):
        '''
        Display a string representation of the hand.
        '''
        output = ''        
        hand_keys = sorted(self.hand.keys())
        for letter in hand_keys:
            for j in range(self.hand[letter]):
                output += letter
        return output</pre>

    <p>Use this <code>__str__</code> method to ensure the grading of 
  the hand's display is consistent.</p>
  </text>
  <coderesponse queuename="Watcher-MITx-6.00x">
    <textbox rows="30" cols="80" mode="python" tabsize="4"/>
    <codeparam>
      <initial_display>
# Paste the entire Hand class in this box
</initial_display>
      <answer_display>
# This is the solution for the update method only. 

    def update(self, word):
        """
        Does not assume that self.hand has all the letters in word.

        Updates the hand: if self.hand does have all the letters to make
        the word, modifies self.hand by using up the letters in the given word.

        Returns True if the word was able to be made with the letter in
        the hand; False otherwise.
        
        word: string
        returns: Boolean (if the word was or was not made)
        """
        # Make a copy of the hand, and try to update it
        new_hand = self.hand.copy()
        for letter in word:
            try:
                new_hand[letter] -= 1
            except KeyError:
                # if 'letter' isn't in the hand, we can't make the word from this hand.
                return False
        for letter in new_hand.keys():
            # If any of the letter counts of the new hand are less than zero after the
            # update, then we can't make the word from this hand.
            if new_hand[letter] &lt; 0:
                return False
        # If we've gotten to here, we must be able to make the word from this hand.
        # Set self.hand to the new, updated hand and return True.
        self.hand = new_hand
        return True
</answer_display>
      <grader_payload>
{"grader": "finger_exercises/L11/handClass/grade_handClass.py"}
</grader_payload>
    </codeparam>
  </coderesponse>
  <p><b>Note:</b> Strings in the test cases in "See full output" are actually srings. When you test your code, they should be myHand.update('shoe') not myHand.update(shoe).</p>
</problem>
