<problem display_name="semordnilap" markdown="null" weight="5.0">
  <p>
    <b>ESTIMATED TIME TO COMPLETE: 20 minutes</b>
  </p>
  <text>
    <p>A <b>semordnilap</b> is a word or a phrase that spells a different word 
      when backwards ("semordnilap" is a semordnilap of "palindromes"). Here are
      some examples:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>nametag / gateman</li>
      <li>dog / god</li>
      <li>live / evil</li>
      <li>desserts / stressed</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Write a recursive program, <code>semordnilap</code>, that 
  takes in two words and says if they are semordnilap.</p>
    <p>This recursive function is not entirely straightforward. There are
  a few things that you need to check the first time you look at the inputs
  that you should not check on subsequent recursive calls: you need to make
  sure that the strings are not single characters, and also you need to be
  sure that the strings are not equal. If you do this check every time you
  call your function, though, this will end up interfering with the recursive
  base case (which we don't want!). </p>
    <p>There's a few 
  different ways you can perform checks on the inputs the first time. The
  first way would be to use <i>keyword arguments</i>. The second way would be to use a
  <i>global variable</i>, which you'll see in the next lecture video; however,
  using global variables is always a bit risky and thus not the best way to do this.</p>
    <p>  The third way to perform checks on the inputs the first time you see
  them, but not any subsequent time, is to use a <i>wrapper function</i>.
  This wrapper function performs some checks, then makes a call to the
  recursive function.</p>
    <p>The idea of a wrapper function is really important. You'll see more
  wrapper functions later. To introduce 
  you to the idea, we are providing you with the wrapper function;
  your job is to write the recursive function <code>semordnilap</code>
  that the wrapper function calls. Here is the wrapper function:</p>
    <pre>def semordnilapWrapper(str1, str2):
    # A single-length string cannot be semordnilap
    if len(str1) == 1 or len(str2) == 1:
        return False

    # Equal strings cannot be semordnilap
    if str1 == str2:
        return False

    return semordnilap(str1, str2)</pre>
    <p>Fill in the definition for <code>semordnilap</code> in the box below.</p>
  </text>
  <coderesponse queuename="Watcher-MITx-6.00x">
    <textbox rows="30" cols="80" mode="python" tabsize="4"/>
    <codeparam>
      <initial_display>
def semordnilap(str1, str2):
    '''
    str1: a string
    str2: a string
    
    returns: True if str1 and str2 are semordnilap;
             False otherwise.
    '''
    # Your code here
</initial_display>
      <answer_display>
def semordnilapWrapper(str1, str2):
    # A single-length string cannot be semordnilap
    if len(str1) == 1 or len(str2) == 1:
        return False

    # Equal strings cannot be semordnilap
    if str1 == str2:
        return False

    return semordnilap(str1, str2)

def semordnilap(str1, str2):
    '''
    str1: a string
    str2: a string
    
    returns: True if str1 and str2 are semordnilap;
             False otherwise.
    '''
    # If strings aren't the same length, they cannot be semordnilap
    if len(str1) != len(str2):
        return False

    # Base case: if the strings are each of length 1, check if they're equal
    if len(str1) == 1:
        return str1 == str2

    # Recursive case: check if the first letter of str1 equals the last letter
    # of str2
    if str1[0] == str2[-1]:
        return semordnilap(str1[1:], str2[:-1])
    else:
        return False
</answer_display>
      <grader_payload>
{"grader": "finger_exercises/L5/semordnilap/grade_semordnilap.py"}
</grader_payload>
    </codeparam>
  </coderesponse>
  <text>
    <p>Note: In programming there are many ways to solve a problem. For your code to check correctly 
  here, though, you must write your recursive function such that you make a recursive call 
  directly to the function <code>semordnilap</code>. Thank you for understanding.
</p>
    <p>
      <section class="hints">
        <h3>Hints</h3>
        <div class="collapsible">
          <header>
            <a href="#" id="id71a">Unequal Strings</a>
          </header>
          <section id="id71a">
            <p> What happens when two strings are not of equal length? What can you immediately return? </p>
          </section>
        </div>
        <div class="collapsible">
          <header>
            <a href="#" id="id71">What should your base case be?</a>
          </header>
          <section id="id71">
            <p>What happens when the strings are of length 1? </p>
          </section>
        </div>
        <div class="collapsible">
          <header>
            <a href="#" id="id72">What should your recursive case be?</a>
          </header>
          <section id="id72">
            <p>Go back to the definition of a semordnilap. What can you say about the first letter of <code>str1</code> and the last letter of <code>str2</code>?</p>
          </section>
        </div>
      </section>
    </p>
    <p><b>If you are getting the error stating that "Your code should be recursive" when you already make a call to <code>semordnilap</code></b>: check your indention -- specifically, a common mistake is that your function and docstring do not start at the same indentation level.
    </p>
  </text>
</problem>
